(Music)
(موسيقى)
Dannielle Hadley: Life in Pennsylvania means just that:
دينييل هادلي: الحياة في بينسيلفينيا تعني هذا فقط:
life without the possibility of parole.
الحياة دون إحتمال إطلاق سراح مشروط.
For us lifers,
بالنسبة لنا نحن الحياتيون
as we call ourselves,
كما نسمي أنفسنا
our only chance for release
فرصتنا الوحيدة للإفراج
is through commutation,
هي من خلال إبدال العقوبة
which has only been granted to two women since 1989,
الذي أتيح لإمرأتين فقط منذ عام 1989
close to 30 years ago.
ما يقرب من 30 سنة مضت.
Our song, "This Is Not Our Home,"
أغنيتنا، "هذا ليس منزلنا"
it tells of our experiences
تحكي عن تجربتنا
while doing life without the possibility of parole.
بينما نحيا دون إحتمال إطلاق سراح مشروط
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Brenda Watkins: I'm a woman.
بريندا واتكينز: أنا إمرأة
I'm a grandmother.
أنا جدة
I'm a daughter.
أنا إبنة
I have a son.
عندي ولد.
I'm not an angel.
أنا لست ملاكا.
I'm not the devil.
أنا لست شيطانا.
I came to jail
دخلت السجن
when I was so young.
عندما كنت صغيرة
I spend my time here
أمضي وقتي هنا
inside these prison walls.
داخل أسوار السجن
Lost friends to death,
مات بعض أصحابي
saw some go home.
غادر بعضهم السجن.
Watch years pass,
مرت علي السنين
people come and go,
أتى الناس وذهبوا
while I do life without parole.
بينما أحيا دون احتمال إطلاق سراح مشروط
I am a prisoner for the wrong I've done.
أنا سجينة بسبب خطأ إقترفته.
I'm doing time here.
وأقضي عقوبتي هنا
This is not my home.
هذا ليس منزلي
Dream of freedom, hope for mercy.
الحلم بالحرية ، والأمل بالعفو
Will I see
هل سأرى
my family
عائلتي
or die alone?
أم أموت وحيدة؟
As the years go by,
بينما تمر السنين
I hold back my tears,
أمنع نفسي من البكاء
because if I cry I'd give in to fear.
لأنني إذا بكيت فإن الخوف قد يتملكني
I must be strong, have to hold on.
علي أن أكون قوية ، صامدة
Gotta get through
يجب أن أتحمل
another year.
سنة أخرى
I am a prisoner for the wrong I've done.
أنا سجينة بسبب خطأ إقترفته
I'm doing time here. This is not my home.
وأقضي عقوبتي هنا هذا ليس منزلي
Dream of freedom, hope for mercy.
الحلم بالحرية ، والأمل بالعفو
Will I see
هل سأرى
my family
عائلتي
or die alone?
أم أموت وحيدة؟
I'm not saying that I'm not guilty,
لا أقول أني لست مذنبة
I'm not saying that I shouldn't pay.
لا أقول أنه ليس علي أن أدفع الثمن
All I'm asking is for forgiveness.
كل ما أطلبه هو العفو
Gotta have hope I'll be free someday.
علي أن أبقى على أمل أني سأكون حرة يوما ما
Is there a place for me
هل هناك مكان لي
in the world out there?
خارج هذا السجن
Will they ever know or care that I'm chained?
هل سيعلمون أني أسيرة وهل سيهتمون؟
Is there redemption for the sin of my younger days?
هل هناك فداء للذنب الذي ارتكبته في الصغر؟
Because I've changed.
لأني قد تغيرت
Lord knows I've changed.
يعلم الله أني تغيرت
I am a prisoner for the wrong I've done.
أنا سجينة بسبب خطأ إقترفته
I'm doing time here. This is not my home.
وأقضي عقوبتي هنا هذا ليس منزلي
Dream of freedom, hope for mercy.
الحلم بالحرية ، والأمل بالعفو
Will I see
هل سأرى
my family
عائلتي
or die alone?
أم أموت وحيدة؟
Will I see
هل سأرى
my family
عائلتي
or die alone?
أم أموت وحيدة؟
I'm known to you as Inmate 008106.
أنا معروفة بالسجينة رقم 008106
Incarcerated 29 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 29 سنة
My name is Brenda Watkins.
إسمي بريندا واتكينز
I was born and raised in Hoffman, North Carolina.
ولدت ونشأت في هوفمان ، كارولاينا الشمالية
This is not my home.
هذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thelma Nichols: Inmate number 0B2472.
ثيلما نيكولس: أنا السجينة رقم 0B2472
I've been incarcerated for 27 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 27 سنة
My name is Thelma Nichols.
إسمي ثيلما نيكولس
I was born and raised in Philadelphia, P.A.
ولدت ونشأت في فيلادلفيا
This is not my home.
هذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
DH: 008494.
السجينة 008494
I've been incarcerated for 27 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 27 سنة
My name is Dannielle Hadley.
إسمي دينييل هادلي
I was born and raised in Philadelphia, P.A,
ولدت ونشأت في فيلادلفيا
and this is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Theresa Battles: Inmate 008309.
تيريزا باتلز: أنا السجينة رقم 008309
I've been incarcerated for 27 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 27 سنة
My name is Theresa Battles.
إسمي تيريزا باتلز
I'm from Norton, New Jersey,
أنا من نورتون ، نيو جيرسي
and this is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Debra Brown: I am known as Inmate 007080.
ديبرا براون: أنا السجينة رقم 007080
I've been incarcerated for 30 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 30 سنة
My name is Debra Brown.
اسمي ديبرا براون
I'm from Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
أنا بيتسبورغ ، بينسلفينيا
This is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Joann Butler: 005961.
جوان باتلر: السجينة 005961
I've been incarcerated for 37 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 37 سنة
My name is Joann Butler,
اسمي جوان باتلر
and I was born and raised in Philadelphia.
ولدت ونشأت في فيلادلفيا
This is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Diane Hamill Metzger: Number 005634.
دايان ميتسجر: السجينة 005634
I've been incarcerated for 39 and one half years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 39 سنة ونصف
My name is Diane Hamill Metzger.
إسمي دايان هامل ميتسجر
I'm from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania,
أنا من فيلادلفيا ، بنسلفانيا
and this is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Lena Brown: I am 004867.
لينا براون: انا السجينة 004867
Incarcerated 40 years.
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 40 سنة
My name is Lena Brown,
اسمي لينا براون
and I was born and raised in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania,
ولدت ونشأت في بيتسبورغ ، بنسلفانيا
and this is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Trina Garnett: My number is 005545.
رقمي هو 005545
My name is Trina Garnett,
اسمي ترينا غارنيت
I've been incarcerated for 37 years,
محكوم علي بالسجن لمدة 37 سنة
since I was 14 years old.
منذ أن كنت في الرابعة عشرة
Born and raised in Chester, Pennsylvania,
ولدت ونشأت في تشيستر ، بنسلفانيا
and this is not my home.
وهذا ليس منزلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Will I see
هل سأرى
my family
عائلتي
or die alone?
أم سأموت وحيدة؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)